<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./sharepoint-delete-list.png" type="Other"
    xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
    <name>Delete SharePoint Online List</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Deletes a SharePoint Online list.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>
				This node deletes a SharePoint list.
			</p>
		</intro>
        <tab name="Settings">
            <option name="SharePoint site">
                There are three ways to specify SharePoint site:
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <i>Root site:</i> Connect to the root site of the domain of the current user (see "Microsoft Connection" input port).
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <i>Web URL:</i> Specify the web URL of a SharePoint site, for example <i>https://mycompany.sharepoint.com</i>.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <i>Group site:</i> Connect to the team site of a particular Office 365 group.
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </option>
            <option name="Subsite">
                If checked, then connect to a (nested) subsite of the SharePoint site specified above. Use the "Refresh" button to list all available subsites
                of the chosen SharePoint site. Note that this allows you only to access the document libraries of the subsite, not those of the parent site(s).
            </option>
            <option name="SharePoint list">
                Here you can select the list you want to overwrite or you can enter the name of a new list you want to create. The drop down menu shows the display name of the list and the internal name it in parentheses.
                Note that if you create a new list (by entering a name manually) the node can not save a list ID and on reexecution the node will search for the ID by the list name.
                In case you changed the list name in SharePoint the node will not be able to find the list. If you reopen the dialog and save it again the ID will be saved in the settings.
            </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Advanced">
            <option name="Connection timeout in seconds">
                Timeout in seconds to establish a connection or 0 for an infinite timeout.
            </option>
            <option name="Read timeout in seconds">
                Timeout in seconds to read data from an established connection or 0 for an infinite timeout.
            </option>
        </tab>

	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Microsoft Connection">
			Microsoft Connection that provides user authentication.
		</inPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>

