<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./sharepoint-list-writer.png" type="Sink"
    xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
    <name>SharePoint Online List Writer</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Writes a SharePoint Online list.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>
				This node writes a KNIME table to a SharePoint list.
			</p>
			
            <p>
                <i>Notes:</i>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        Writing tables with more than a few hundred rows can take long time. Overwriting an existing table
                        can be also very slow in case a lot of rows need to be deleted.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        This node exports the ID of the written list to a flow variable called <tt>sharepoint_list_id</tt>. The ID can be
                        be used in subsequent nodes to control the <tt>list</tt> setting via flow variable.
                    </li>
                </ul>
			</p>
			
			<p>
            <b>KNIME column type support</b><br/>
            </p>

            <p>
			<u>Fully supported KNIME column types:</u>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <i>String and string-compatible columns</i> map to <a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/office/list-and-library-column-types-and-options-0d8ddb7b-7dc7-414d-a283-ee9dca891df7"><i>Multiple lines of text</i></a>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <i>Integer columns</i> map to <a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/office/list-and-library-column-types-and-options-0d8ddb7b-7dc7-414d-a283-ee9dca891df7"><i>Number</i></a>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <i>Boolean columns</i> map to <a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/office/list-and-library-column-types-and-options-0d8ddb7b-7dc7-414d-a283-ee9dca891df7"><i>Yes/no</i></a>
                </li>
            </ul>
            </p>

            <p>
            <u>Partially supported KNIME columns types:</u>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <i>Long columns</i> map to <a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/office/list-and-library-column-types-and-options-0d8ddb7b-7dc7-414d-a283-ee9dca891df7"><i>Number</i></a>.
                    The node will fail for more than 15 significant digits
                    (digits which remain after leading and trailing zeros are
                    removed, i.e. in "401220500000" the digits "4012205" are
                    significant and in "0.0004050114" the digits "4050114" are
                    significant).
                </li>
                <li>
                    <i>Double columns</i> map to <a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/office/list-and-library-column-types-and-options-0d8ddb7b-7dc7-414d-a283-ee9dca891df7"><i>Number</i></a>.
                    The node will fail for infinity, NaN and values outside of
                    [1.79E308,-1.79E308], as well as for numbers with more than
                    15 significant digits.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <i>Local Date and Local Date Time columns</i> map to <a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/office/list-and-library-column-types-and-options-0d8ddb7b-7dc7-414d-a283-ee9dca891df7"><i>
                    Date and Time</i></a>, which stores a UTC timestamp with second-precision. Hence, values from KNIME are mapped to an instant in UTC
                    and truncated to second-precision. For example, 2022-02-02 08:00:00 is stored as 2022-02-02 08:00:00 UTC. The node will fail for values before 1900-01-01 00:00:00 UTC and
                    after 8900-12-31 23:59:59 UTC.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <i>Zoned Date Time columns</i> map to <a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/office/list-and-library-column-types-and-options-0d8ddb7b-7dc7-414d-a283-ee9dca891df7">
                    <i>Date and Time</i></a>, which stores a UTC timestamp with second-precision. Hence, Zoned Date Time values are converted to the UTC timezone and truncated to second-precision.
                    For example, 2022-02-02 08:00:00 CET is stored as
                    2022-02-02 07:00:00 UTC. The node will fail for values before 1900-01-01 00:00:00 UTC and after 8900-12-31 23:59:59 UTC.
                </li>

            </ul>
            </p>

            <p>
            <u>Unsupported KNIME column types:</u><br/>
            All column types that do not belong to the above categories are unsupported and the node cannot be executed, since there is no corresponding type in SharePoint Online.
            </p>
            <p><b>Note:</b> The scopes required by this node have to be consented
            to at least once interactively by the user or workspace admin, especially for scopeless
            secrets.
            Please refer to the <a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/community_hub_secrets_guide/index.html#secret_type_azure_scopes">documentation</a>
            to find out which scopes are required.
            </p>
		</intro>
        <tab name="Settings">
            <option name="SharePoint site">
                There are three ways to specify SharePoint site:
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <i>Root site:</i> Connect to the root site of the domain of the current user (see "Microsoft Connection" input port).
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <i>Web URL:</i> Specify the web URL of a SharePoint site, for example <i>https://mycompany.sharepoint.com</i>.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <i>Group site:</i> Connect to the team site of a particular Office 365 group.
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </option>
            <option name="Subsite">
                If checked, then connect to a (nested) subsite of the SharePoint site specified above. Use the "Refresh" button to list all available subsites
                of the chosen SharePoint site. Note that this allows you only to access the document libraries of the subsite, not those of the parent site(s).
            </option>
            <option name="SharePoint list">
                Here you can select the list you want to overwrite or you can enter the name of a new list you want to create. The drop down menu shows the display name of the list and the internal name it in parentheses.
                Note that if you create a new list (by entering a name manually) the node can not save a list ID and on reexecution the node will search for the ID by the list name.
                In case you changed the list name in SharePoint the node will not be able to find the list. If you reopen the dialog and save it again the ID will be saved in the settings.
            </option>
            <option name="Overwrite policy if list exists">
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <i>Overwrite</i> if the list already exists it will get overwritten or a new list will be created.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <i>Fail</i> if the list already exists.
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Advanced">
            <option name="Connection timeout in seconds">
                Timeout in seconds to establish a connection or 0 for an infinite timeout.
            </option>
            <option name="Read timeout in seconds">
                Timeout in seconds to read data from an established connection or 0 for an infinite timeout.
            </option>
        </tab>

	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Credential (JWT)">
			A JWT credential as provided by the Microsoft Authenticator node.
		</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="Table">
			The table to be written to SharePoint.
		</inPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>

