<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Source" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.10" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
    <name>Sharepoint Online Connector (Labs)</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Connects to Sharepoint in order to read/write files in downstream nodes.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
         <intro>
            <p>This node connects to Sharepoint. The resulting output port allows downstream nodes to access
            the Sharepoint data of a <i>site</i> as a file system, e.g. to read or write files and folders,
            or to perform other file system operations (browse/list files, copy, move, ...).
            </p>
            
            <p><b>Path syntax:</b> Paths for Sharepoint are specified with a UNIX-like syntax, /mydrive/myfolder/myfile. An absolute
            for Sharepoint consists of:
                <ol>
                    <li>A leading slash ("/").</li>
                    <li>Followed by the name of a drive (a.k.a. document library) ("mydrive" in the above example), followed by a slash.</li>
                    <li>Followed by the path to the file ("myfolder/myfile" in the above example).</li>
                </ol>
            </p>
        </intro>
            
        <option name="Sharepoint site">
         	There are three ways to specify Sharepoint site:
           	<ul>
           		<li>
           			Using a root site.
           		</li>
          		<li>
           			User can specify the web URL of the site
           		</li>
           		<li>
           			Team site: user can specify name of the group
           		</li>
           	</ul>
        </option>
        <option name="URL">
           	The web URL of the site.
        </option>
        <option name="Select group name">
        	Select the group name.
        </option>
        <option name="Subsite">
        	It is possible to connect to one of the subsites of a given site. Use the fetch button to list all available subsites.
        </option>
	    <option name="Working directory">
	        Specifies the <i>working directory</i> using the path syntax explained above. The working directory must be specified as an absolute path. A working directory allows downstream
	        nodes to access files/folders using <i>relative</i> paths, i.e. paths that do not have a leading slash. If not specified, the default working directory
	        is "/".
	    </option>
	    <option name="Connection timeout in seconds">
	        Timeout in seconds to establish a connection or 0 for an infinite timeout. 
	    </option>
	    <option name="Read timeout in seconds">
	        Timeout in seconds to read data from an established connection or 0 for an infinite timeout.
	    </option>
        

    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
    	<inPort index="0" name="Azure Connection">
    		Azure Connection
    	</inPort>
   		<outPort index="0" name="Sharepoint File System Connection">
   			Sharepoint File System Connection
   		</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
